Yes, welcome to this tutorial
in the Texture Mapping series.
This third tutorial is intended
to show you, how you can place a
texture of a tree
trunk, which you
see here, onto
a simple cylinder.
We have used two textures
here, one texture for the trunk
and another texture here for the
cross-section of the tree trunk.
And I will show
you in just a few
steps how easily it is possible
to get the texture
into the right
place with the
help of UV Mapping.
Then we start with the Blender
Default screen, here the cube.
I delete the cube and add a
cylinder, which I scale a bit in Z.
We see here that
we will not go into
detail on the
modeling of the tree
stump, but only on
how we can place
an optimal texture
onto this cylinder.
Well, let's now take a
look at the UV Editing tools.
We also see here, as in one of the earlier
tutorials, that the cylinder
is already mapped correctly.
At this point here, we see here the
side of the cylinder and the top- and
Bottom side of the cylinder.
This is the case with default objects.