Welcome warmly to this tutorial
in the series on Texture Mapping.
This third tutorial will show you,
how to apply texture to a tree trunk.
Here you can see a simple cylinder that can be mapped.
We have used two textures here.
One texture for the trunk and another
texture from the cross-section of the tree trunk.
And I will show you in just a few steps how easy it is to get
the texture onto the correct place with help of UV-Mapping.
Starting now, we begin using the default configuration
of Blender on this screen; take a look at the cube here.
I delete the cube and give a cylinder instead.
We see here that we are now not
approaching the
modeling of the stump any
closer, but rather
focusing on how we can
optimally map the
texture onto this cylinder.
Well...
we now take a look at the UV-mapping
on the... we also see in one of our earlier
Tutorials, if the cylinder is already
correctly mapped at this location here.
We see here the side of the cylinder and
the upper and lower surfaces of the cylinder.
This is the case with default objects.