Welcome to this tutorial in
the series Texture Mapping.
This third tutorial is intended to show you, how you can map a
texture of a tree
trunk, which you
can see here, onto
a simple cylinder.
We have used two textures here.
One texture for the trunk and another
texture here from the cut of the tree trunk.
And I will show you in just a few steps, how easy this is possible,
here to get the
texture to the right
place with the
help of UV mapping.
Then we start with the Blender Default
Screen, here the cube.
I delete the cube and add a
cylinder, which I scale a little in Z.
We see here that we are not approaching the modeling of the tree
stump here now, but
only on how we can
optimally map the
texture onto this cylinder.
Good, we now look at the
UV-Mapping-Modellierungen.
We see here also in one of the earlier
Tutorials, is the cylinder already correctly mapped.
At this point here, we see here the side of the
cylinder and the top and the bottom of the cylinder.
That is the case with default objects.
If we however