Yes, welcome to this
tutorial in Redex Champirping.
This third tutorial is
supposed to show you
how to make a texture of
a tree trunk, see here.
On a simple
zilinder, in the middle.
We used two textures
here A texture for the trunk.
And another texture here
from the slide of the tree trunk.
And I'll show you in a few a
few Steps how simple this is
possible, here
the texture in the
right place Get help
from the UV-Mapin.
Then we start with the blender default.
The buf is turning here.
I delete the buffet and add a
zilinder to whom
I scalar in Zett.
We see here that we are not closer
to the modeling of the tree stance
and only how we
optimally the Texture
can be in the
middle of this zilinder.
Well, we are now looking at the
UV Mapin, The UV-Mapin do tools.
We also see here in
an earlier one Tutorials.
The zilinder
already dubbed here.
We'll see that here
Page of the zilinder and
The upper and the
Underside of the zilinder.
This is the case with the
photo objects If we completely ...