Yes, welcome to this tutorial
in the series Texture Mapping.
This third tutorial is intended to show you how you can map the
texture of a tree trunk, which you see here, onto a simple cylinder.
We have used two textures here one texture for the
trunk and another texture here from the cut of the tree trunk.
And I will show you in a few steps how easy it is to get
the texture to the right place with the help of UV mapping.
Then we start with the Blender Default
Screen here the cube.
I delete the cube and add a
cylinder which I scale a bit in Z.
We see here that we are now
not going into the
modeling of the tree stump, but only
on how we
can optimally map the texture onto this cylinder.
Well, we now look at the UV Editing
tools.
We also see here in one of the earlier
tutorials, the cylinder is already correctly mapped.
At this point here, we see here the
side of the cylinder and the top and
bottom of the cylinder.
That is the case with default objects.