Yes, welcome to this tutorial
in the series Texture Mapping.
This third tutorial is intended
to show you, how to apply a
texture of a tree
trunk, which you
see here, onto
a simple cylinder.
We have used two textures
here, one texture for the
trunk and another texture here
from the cut of the tree trunk.
And I will show you in a few
steps how easy it is to get
the texture in the right place
with the help of UV mapping.
Then let's start with the Blender
default screen here with the cube.
I delete the cube and add a
cylinder, which I scale a bit in Z.
We see here that we will not go into
the
modeling of the tree
stump in detail, but only
on, how we can apply optimal
texture to this cylinder.
Well, now let's take a
look at the UV editing tools.
We also see here in one of the earlier
tutorials, the cylinder is
already properly mapped.
At this point here, we see here the
side of the cylinder and the top and
bottom of the cylinder.
This is the case with default objects.