Yes, a warm welcome to this tutorial
in the series Texture Mapping.
This third tutorial is supposed to show you, how you can apply
a texture of a tree trunk, which you see here, to a simple cylinder.
We have used two textures here.
One texture for the trunk and another
texture from the cut of the tree trunk.
And I will show you in a few short steps, how easy it is to
get the texture to the right place with the help of UV-Mapping.
Then we start with the Blender default
screen.
Here is the cube.
I delete the cube and add a
cylinder, which I scale a bit in Z.
We see here that
we are not going into
the details of modeling
the tree stump,
but only into how we
can map the texture
onto this cylinder
in an optimal way.
Alright, we now look at the UV editing
tools.
We also saw in one of the earlier tutorials
that the cylinder is already correctly mapped.
At this point here, we
see the side of
Cylinders and the top
and the underside of the cylinder.
This is the case with default objects.