Welcome warmly to this tutorial
inthe series Texture Mapping.
This third tutorial will show you,how to map the texture of a tree
trunk, which you can see here,onto a simple cylinder.
We have used two textures here.
One texture for the trunk and
anothertexture from the cut on the tree trunk.
I will show you in just a few steps,how easy it is to do this.
Here's how to get the texture at the
right place with help from UV Mapping.
Then we start with the Blender Default Screen, here the cube.
I delete the cube and give a cylinder instead, which I scale up by Z.
We see that now we're not going closer to modeling the tree
trunk but only how we can map the texture optimally on this cylinder.
Good, let's take a look at the UV Mapping technology.
We also see here in one of the earlier tutorials
that the cylinder is already correctly mapped here.
At this point here.
We see the side of the cylinder and
the top and bottom sides of the cylinder.
This is the case by default for default objects.
However, when we are dealing with completely