Welcome to this tutorial on
the Texture Mapping series.
This third tutorial will show you how to map a texture of
a tree stem you see here to a simple cylinder.
We have used two textures here.
One for the stem and another here from the cut of the tree stem.
And I will show you in a few steps how easy it is to do this.
Here the texture to the right place
with help from UV mapping to get.
Then we start with the Blender default screen, here is the cube.
I delete the cube and give a cylinder to it, which I scale slightly.
We see here that we are not going to focus on modeling the root of the
tree here, but
only on how we can
optimally map the
texture to this cylinder.
Good, we are now watching the UV mapping map series.
We also see here in one of the earlier tutorials, is
the cylinder already correctly mapped? There, here.
We see the side of the cylinder and
the upper and lower sides of the cylinder.
This is the case with default objects.