Yes, welcome to this tutorial
in the Dexter Mepping series.
This third tutorial will show you
how you can center a texture of
a tree trunk, which you see
here, on a simple cylinder. cylinder.
We have used two textures
here used here, one texture for the
trunk and another texture here
from the cut of the tree trunk.
And I'll show you in a few steps
how easy it is to get the texture in
the right place with the help of UV
mapping. with the help of UV mapping.
Then we start with the Blender
Diefold screen here the cube.
I delete the cube,
I add a cylinder
to it, which I
scale a little in Z.
We can see here that we are not going
to the modeling of the tree stump, but only
how we can optimally center the texture
on this cylinder. texture to this cylinder.
All right, let's take a look
at the UV editing tools.
We also see here in one of
the earlier tutorials that the
cylinder is already correctly
mapped at this point here.
Here we see the side of the cylinder
and the underside of the cylinder.
This is the case with diefold
objects, even if we completely...