Yes, welcome to this tutorial
in the Texture Mapping series.
This third tutorial will show you how to map a texture of
a tree trunk, which you see here, onto a simple cylinder.
We used two textures here.
One texture for the trunk and another texture
here from the cross-section of the tree trunk.
And I'll show you in just a few steps how easy it is to get
the texture in the right place here with the help of UV-Mapping.
Then we'll start with the Blender Default
Screen.
Here's the cube.
I delete the cube and add a
cylinder, which I scale a bit in Z.
We see here that
we won't go into
detail about the
modeling of the tree
trunk, but only about
how we can optimally
map the texture
onto this cylinder.
Good.
Now we'll take a look at the UV editing tools.
We also see here in one of the earlier
tutorials, the cylinder is already mapped correctly.
At this point here.
Here we see the side of the cylinder
and the top and bottom of the cylinder.
That's the case with default objects.
But let's take completely...