Yes, welcome to this tutorial
in the series of Texture Mapping.
This third tutorial is meant to show you how to map a texture
of a tree trunk, which you can see here, onto a simple cylinder.
We have used two textures here, one texture for the
trunk and another texture here from the cut of the tree trunk.
And I'll show you in a few short steps, how easy it is to
get the texture in the right place with the help of UV Mapping.
Then we start with the Blender default
screen here, the cube.
I delete the cube and add a
cylinder, which I scale a bit in the Z direction.
We see here that we will not go into
details
about modeling the tree stump, but
only
about how we can optimally map textures onto this cylinder.
Good, we now look at the UV Editing
Tools.
We also see in one of our earlier tutorials,
the cylinder is already correctly mapped.
At this point here, we see the side of the cylinder and the top and
bottom of the cylinder.
This is the case with default objects.