Yes, welcome to this tutorial in the series Texture Mapping.
This third tutorial should show you how to apply a texture of
a tree trunk, which you can see here, onto a simple cylinder.
We have used two textures here, one for the
trunk and another texture for the cut of the tree trunk.
And I will show you in a few simple steps how easy it is to
place the texture in the right position with the help of UV mapping.
Then we start with the Blender Default Screen, here the cube.
I delete the cube and add a cylinder, which I scale a bit in Z.
We see here that we will not go into the
modeling of the tree stump in detail, but
only on how to apply optimal texture to this cylinder.
Alright, let's now look at the UV Editing Tools.
We also see here that in one of the previous
tutorials, the cylinder is already correctly mapped.
At this point here, we see the
side of the cylinder and the top and
bottom of the cylinder.
This is the case with default objects.