Yes, welcome to this tutorial in
the series on Texture Mapping.
This third tutorial is meant
to show you how you can map a
tree trunk texture, which you
see here, onto
a simple cylinder.
We have used two textures here, one for the trunk
and another for the
cross-section of the tree trunk.
And I will show you in just
a few steps how easy it
is to correctly place the
texture using UV mapping.
We start with the Blender
Default Screen with the cube.
I delete the cube and add a cylinder,
which I scale a bit in the Z direction.
Here, we see that we are not going to
focus
on modeling the tree stump, but on how
we
can optimally map textures onto this cylinder.
Alright, now let's look at the UV Editing
tools.
In one of the previous tutorials, we see
that the cylinder is already properly mapped.
At this spot here,
we see here the
side of the cylinder
and the top and
bottom of the cylinder.
This is the case with default objects.