Yes, welcome to this tutorial
in the Texture Mapping series.
This third tutorial is designed to show you
how to create a texture of
a tree trunk that you see here on a simple
Cylinders.
We used two textures here.
One texture for the
trunk and another
Texture here from
the cut of the tree trunk.
And I'll show you in a few
Steps, how easy
this is possible,
here the texture
to the right place
with Get help from UV mapping.
Then we start with the Blender
Default Screen the cube here.
I'm deleting the
Cube and add a
cylinder that
i scale something to Z.
We see here that we are not here now
elaborate on
the modelling of the tree stump,
but only on how we
can apply optimal texture to these
Can map cylinders.
Good, now let's look at UV editing
Tools.
We also see here in one of the earlier
tutorials, the cylinder is already mapped correctly.
On and the bottom of the cylinder.
This is the case with default objects.