Welcome to this tutorial in
the series Texture Mapping.
This third tutorial is going to show
you how to make a tree trunk texture.
So the first thing you see here is
that you can map it to a simple cylinder.
We used two textures here.
One texture for the trunk and
another texture here from the trunk cut.
And I'm going to show you in
a few steps how easy that is.
The texture is then placed in the right
place with the help of the UV mapping.
Then we start with the Blender
Default screen, here's the cube.
I erase the cube and add a cylinder
to it, which I scale a little bit in Z.
We see here that we are not here
now closer to the modelling of the
The main objective of this project
is to improve the quality of the
I can map cylinders.
Okay, let's look at
the UV editing tools.
We see here in one of the earlier tutorials,
the cylinder is already mapped correctly.
At this point here, we
see here the side of the
Cylinders and the top
and bottom of the cylinder.
That's the case
with default objects.
But if we turn
around completely,